https://www.system-concepts.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to contentSystem Concepts core beliefs regarding user privacy and data protectionWe have a duty of care to any persons in our dataProcessing and collection of data is carried out only when necessaryWe will never sell, rent or otherwise distribute or make public your personal informationWe will seek explicit consent for any distribution list, we don’t spam or add you to newsletter distributions without your consentRelevant LegislationAlong with our business and internal systems, this website is designed to comply with the following legislation with regards to data protection and user privacy:UK Data Protection Act 2018EU Data Protection Directive 1995 (DPD)EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR)Personal information that this website collects and why we collect iti) Site visitation trackingLike many websites, this site uses Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website in order to improve our serviceGoogle analytics records data such as location, IP address, internet browser and device, none of this information personally identifies you to us or is used to personally identify you to us.GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found on Google’s developer guides.Disabling cookies on your internet browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website.ii) NewsletterWe distribute a newsletter through Mailchimp, who provide our email marketing service, if you choose to join our email newsletter, the email address that you submit to us will be processed by MailChimp. We consider MailChimp to be a third party data processor (see below). The email address that you submit will not be stored within this website’s own database or in any of our internal computer systems.Your email address will remain within MailChimp’s database for as long as we continue to use MailChimp’s services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by clicking this link or by sending an email to enquiries@system-concepts.com. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.iii) Contact forms / enquiriesShould you choose to contact us using the enquiry email link or any other system concepts email, none of the data that you supply will be stored by this website or passed to / be processed by any of the third party data processors. Instead the data will be collated into an email and sent to us over the Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP). Our SMTP servers are protected by TLS (sometimes known as SSL) meaning that the email content is encrypted.Third Party data processorsGoogle (Privacy policy)Mailchimp (Privacy policy)Data ControllerThe data controller of this website is: System Concepts Limited, a UK Private Limited Company with company number: 205 5814:Registered Operating office:3rd Floor Headland House 72 Acton St London WC1X 9NBData Protection officerMr. Darren Smith Director, System Concepts Ltd Tel: 020 7240 3388Email: darren@system-concepts.comChanges to this policyThis privacy policy may change from time to time in line with legislation or industry developments. We will not explicitly inform our clients or website users of these changes. Instead, we recommend that you check this page occasionally for any policy changes. Specific policy changes and updates are mentioned in the change log below. Sign up to our newsletters
Select a newsletter...Health, Safety & ErgonomicsUX, Usabilility & AccessibilityBoth newsletters
Please send me your Health, Safety and Ergonomics newsletter
Please send me your User Experience newsletter
We are using cookies to give you the best experience on our website.You can find out more about which cookies we are using or switch them off in settings. Accept
Close GDPR Cookie Settings
Privacy Overview
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Powered by  GDPR Cookie Compliance Privacy OverviewThis website uses cookies so that we can provide you with the best user experience possible. Cookie information is stored in your browser and performs functions such as recognising you when you return to our website and helping our team to understand which sections of the website you find most interesting and useful. Strictly Necessary CookiesStrictly Necessary Cookie should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for cookie settings.
Enable or Disable Cookies
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that every time you visit this website you will need to enable or disable cookies again. Enable All Save Changes
